Guide to the Ester Hernandez Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Personal Writings, Projects, Series 2; .5 linear ft.
  - Luis Cervantez: Talking About Chicano Zootsuiters (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - A Pachuco's Perspective of the 1940's; includes interview with Ramon (Zala) Nevel (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Mexican Arts and Crafts: A Curriculum Guide for Teachers (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - NALAC(National Association of Latin Artists) Keynote Address: An Artist's Perspective (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Lydia Mendoza: La Medrina (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Lydia Mendoza and Astrid Hadid: lecture at Stanford, 9/10/1998 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Tres Flores: Lydia Mendoza, Astrid Hadad, and Selena, lecture at Stanford, 5/2/99 [Mac 3.5" disk] (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Teaching Art to the Disabled: lecture series excerpts, Japan, 1/99 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Copyright registrations (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - The Holy Tree, Watsonville, CA, Summer, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Immigrant Woman's Dress (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Postcard Artwork (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Writings - unpublished/unedited (Box 37, Folder 15)
- Personal Papers, Series 3; 5 linear ft.
  The material in Series 3, Subseries: General, covers nearly thirty years of Hernandez's career, from her student days at UC-Berkeley in the early 1970s through art exhibits and academic conferences in the late 1990s. Included are exhibit catalogs and announcements, news articles, flyers, grant proposals and applications, conference announcements, etc., all of which either mention Hernandez as a participant or feature her artwork. The two remaining subseries, Family and School Yearbooks contain information, correspondence and photographs of Hernandez's family, and yearbooks from junior high school through junior college.
  - General, Subseries 3.1
    - Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - La Razon Mestiza II, Special Edition, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Bibliography of Writings on La Mujer: UC Chicano Studies Library, Berkeley, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Mexican Museum Newsletter, re: Ester's grant for "Alternatives in Education" - Aztlan Cultural sponsoring organization, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Chisme Arte, magazine, La Mujer Special Issue [2 copies], 1977 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - El Fuego de Aztlan, Calenderio, UC Berkeley [vol.1, #2], 1977 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Fuego de Aztlan, vol.1, #3 [May, 1977], art and writings by Ester (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - La Raza Law Students de California - Info Brochure, UC Berkeley, 1977-1978 [2 copies] (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - California Arts Council: Ester's Residency, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - La Razon Mestiza II, Special Edition, Census 1980 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Decontaminating Amerika: The Art of Ester Hernandez, in Revista literaria de El Tecolote, SF, CA, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Intertribal Friendship House, Oakland, CA: mural with Jean LaMarr, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Intertribal Friendship House, Oakland, CA: mural with Jean LaMarr, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Personal Reflections: Masks by Chicano and Native American Artists in CA, La Raza Bookstore, Sacramento, CA, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - La Raza Graphics - Silkscreen Project - Mujeres, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - The Mural Project, SF Art Institute, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - 1st Festival Internacional de la Raza, Centro Cutural Tijuana, MX, curator Felipe Ehrenberg, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Hispanic Link Weekly Report, Washington D.C., 1984 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Artistas Indigenas, Austin, TX, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      Marsha Gomez: visiual director, exhibitor
    - El Tecolate, San Francisco, CA, Sept-Oct 1984 (Box 38, Folder 14)
      [Ester's Weaving of the Disappeared on first page of supplement]
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, brochures, flyers, newspapers, etc. (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - The Women Artists Slide Library - International Women's Day, Battersea Arts Centre, London, England, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - South and Central American Information Center (SAIIC), Oakland, CA, publications 1980s (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Cinco de Mayo - A Case of Identity, Oakland Tribune, ca. 1986 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Mexican American Legal Defense and Education Fund (MALDEF) - Annual Report, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Artistas Mexicano-Americanos de San Francisco. California, Exposicion Catalog, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - La Nueva ley de Immigracion, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - La Ventana, Sonoma County's Hispanic Newsletter - Interview with Ester, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - The Goldie's Award - SF Bay Guardian, San Francisco, CA, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Centro de Bellas Artes Galeria, Imagenes de Mujeres, Fresno, CA, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Suplemento Gaceta - Las Mujeres Chicanas Quermos Abrir Las Puertas Para Comunicar con Los Mexicanas, Mexico, FD, article by Cecelia Burciaga, 1989 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - 1990 Art Activities (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - 1991 Art Activities (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - 1992 Miscellaneous Activities (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - 1992 Miscellaneous Papers; Reviews of Ester's work and other artists, 1994. (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Harassment case, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Richard Schultz - infringement problem, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous activities, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous activities, 1994 [1 of 2] (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous activities, 1994 [2 of 2] (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous art activities, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - 1996 art activities (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - 1997 art activities (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - 1998 activities (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Alma Corazon y Vida; Roma, Italia, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Artistas Chicanas - Symposium - Uc Santa Barbara, CA 1991 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - The Black Madonna Exhibit - Poland 1991 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Cine Accion 5th Annual Cine Latino - Sun Mad - The Movie (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Celebration of Craftswomen - 1997 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Centro - latino Mural, SF, CA 1991 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Congresssional Hispanic Caucus Poster - 1991 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Dos Decados de Artistas Chicanas - UC Santa Barbara, 1994 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - The Fight in the Fields - Cesar Chavez and the Farmworkers' Struggle, film, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - International Women's Day, La Pena, Austin, TX, 1990 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Intimate Lives - Women and Their Work, Austin, TX, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Mujer: Palabras y Visiones, La Pena, Austin, TX, 1992 - International Women's Day (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - NACCS [National Association for Chicana and Chicano Studies] Sacramento, CA 1997 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - NALAC [National Association of Latino Arts and Culture] 1992 - keynote speech (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - NALAC [National Association of Latino Arts and Culture] 1995 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Open Studio: Ester with Juan Fuentes and Nancy Hom at Galeria De la Raza, SF, 1994 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Pasion por Frida Exhibit, Mexico City, 1992 - correspondence (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - The Power of Feminist Art, Abrams, Inc., 1993-1994 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - UC Berkeley Chicana Latina Conference, 11/97 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - NACCS [National Association for Chicana and Chicano Studies], 1999 - General Information (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Mumia Abu Jamal (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1999 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - 1999 Activities (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Family, Subseries 3.2
    - Family Photos, 1930s [1 of 4], photocopies (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Family Photos, 1940s [2 of 4], photocopies (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Family Photos, 1950s [3 of 4], photocopies (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Family Photos, 1960s [4 of 4], photocopies (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Early Family Photos, 1916-1940s (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Family Photos, 1940s-1950s - uncles (military), photocopies (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Class photo, Washington Junior High School, Dinuba, CA; elementary school diploma, 1958; high school graduation Congressional Greetings (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Family 1970s: Correspondence, miscellaneous material, photo (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - UC Berkeley, 1970s: University Without Walls guide; Chicano Graduation Program (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Family 1980s: Correspondence; father's death notice, etc. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Driver's licenses, passports (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Family 1990s: correspondence, etc. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Family 1990s: letters from sisters. (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Family: Death of sister Hope Macias: news articles, memorial messages, etc. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Ester' astrological chart (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Information regarding Dinuba, CA: news articles, slides, etc. (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Patrick Macias (nephew): writings appearing in news articles, photocopies (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Letters to parents, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Family photos I [1 of 2], photographs (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Family photos I [2 of 2], photographs and slides (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Family photos II [1 of 2], photographs and slides (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Family photos II [2 of 2], photographs and slides (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - School Yearbooks, Subseries 3.3
    - Washington Junior High School Yearbook, 1957 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Washington Junior High School Yearbook, 1958 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Dinuba High School Yearbook, 1959 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Dinuba High School Yearbook, 1960 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Dinuba High School Yearbook, 1961 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Dinuba High School Yearbook, 1962 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Reedley College Yearbook, 1963 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Reedley College Yearbook, 1964 (Box 96, Folder 3)
- Photographs/Slides/Negatives, Series 4; 3.5 linear ft.
  Series 4 presents a visual journey through Hernandez's professional and personal life. Images found in this series include: early 1970s photographs of orange pickers working in California's Central Valley, Hernandez's sister artists of Las Mujeras Muralistas and her work with Oakland school children through the California Arts Council; exhibit installations, exhibit openings, print shop visits, and conferences throughout the 1980s and 1990s,; and personal photographs covering the 1970s-1990s.
  - Posada de Colores, California Arts Council, Oakland (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Arizona State University Hispanic Research Center: Lithograph - Segura Publ., 1998 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Brandywine Press, 1991; 1996 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Centro Latino Mural, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Crearte, Minneapolis, MN, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Galeria de la Raza, 1990s (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Lab Ova, Yokahama, Japan, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Japan Trip, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - MACLA [Movimiento de Arte y Cultura Latino American]: Lydia Mendoza, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Mexican Museum, SF, 1991; 1998 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Mexican Museum, Chicago, 1987; 1989[?], 1994 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Mission Cultural Center, SF: Day of the Dead, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - NAACS [National Association for Chicana and Chicano Studies] Conference, Sacramento, 1999[?] (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - NALAC [National Association of LAtino Arts and Cultures] Conference, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - San Francisco Art Institute (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Self Help Graphics, LA, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Smithsonian Institute, Washington D.C., opening, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Wright Art Gallery, UCLA; CARA, SF, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - UC Santa Barbara, Chicana Women Artists, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - California Arts Council, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Sun Mad, the Video, Dinuba, CA, ca. 1995 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Sun Mad Installation, 1989 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Sun Maid [Research], n.d.; photocopies (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Mutual Influences, Guadalupe Arts Center, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - St John's Mural, Oakland, CA, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Hispanic Caucus, 1991 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Pasion por Frida, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - The Holy Tree, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Mujeres Muralistas: Irene, Graciela, etc., ca. 1970s (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Studies for pastel: "Puras Papas", ca. 1999 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Self-printing, Oakland, CA, February, 1984 (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Color positives [search for titles], n.d. (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Personal photographs/slides, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Ester -photos/portraits [1 of 2], n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Ester -photos/portraits [2 of 2], n.d. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Renee Moreno, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Graciela Iturbide: negatives, SF visits, Ester's visit to Mexico; 1990,; 1991;; 1991 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Alice Walker: negatives (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Astrid Haddad: negatives (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Lydia Mendoza: slides of visits to CA, 1982; 1985 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Lydia Mendoza: slides of Ester's visit to Houston, TX, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Lydia Mendoza: negatives (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Family photos: negatives (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Negatives, 1970s (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Negatives [1 of 2], 1980s (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Negatives [2 of 2], 1980s (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Negatives [1 of 4], 1990s (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Negatives [2 of 4], 1990s (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Negatives [3 of 4], 1990s (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Negatives [4 of 4], 1990s (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Negatives: Las Mujeras Muralistas, 1970s[?] (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Galeria de la Raza, 1980s (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Berryessa Flea Market, San Jose, CA, 1987; photographs (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Orange pickers, 1973[?]; photographs (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - La Lonely, Fresno, CA, 1993; photographs (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Low Rider Bikes, ca. 1997; photographs (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Screenprinting, Oakland, CA, 1982; photographs (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - New Orleans, LA, 1988; photographs (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Monoprinting, Oakland, CA, 1990; photographs (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Russian River, CA, 1986; photographs (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Day of the Dead, Home Altar, Oakland, CA, 1990; photographs (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Photo session, Oakland, CA, 1987; photographs (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - New Mexico, 1990; photographs (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - All Indian Rodeo, Fallon, NV, ca. 1983; photographs (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Mendocino Coast, CA, 1989; photographs (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Calistoga, CA, 1986; photographs (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Barbeque, San Francisco, CA, 1993; photographs (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - High Sierras, 1993; photographs (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Mexico City, 1996; photographs (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Japan Tour, 1999; photographs (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Guadalupe, Az: Yaqui Village, 1998; photographs (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - California Indian Protest March, 1998; photographs (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Charreada, Sunol, CA, 1986; photographs (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Centro Cultural de Coyoacan, 1991; photographs (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Banda Dance, Gilroy, CA [1 of 2], 1992; photographs (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Banda Dance, Gilroy, CA [2 of 2], 1992; photographs (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Carnival, San Francisco, 1989; photographs (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Carnival, San Francisco, 1996; photographs (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Colectivo Sol, Mexico City, 1991; photographs (Box 50, Folder 17)
- Audio Visual, Series 5; 1. 5 linear ft.
  Series 5 contains mostly videocassettes (VHS) of subjects that have interested Hernandez through the years. Included are: Cesar Chavez Memorial, 1993; Sun Mad-the Movie, 1995; Oral History Interview with Lucy Hernandez (Ester's mother), 1994; Pilots of Aztlan: Flights of the Royal Chicano Air Force, n.d.; Ester Hernandez - Self Help Graphics, Los Angeles, 1991; Ester Hernandez, A Defiant Eye, January, 1993, VHS cassette; and others.
  - Dia de los Muertos, n.d., super 8 and 8mm/400 ft (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Cesar Chavez Memorial, 40 acres, Delano, CA, April 1993, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Tiempo Latino, May 1986, Ester Hernandez, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Vida Awards, Latin Nights, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Lucy Hernandez, Oral/Visual History, Dinuba, CA, 11/25/1994, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Pilots of Aztlan: Flights of the Royal Chicano Air Force, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Films/Video by Francisco X. Camplis: Los Desarraigados; Coyolxauhqui; Musicos; Drawing Class; Margarita, 1995, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Sun Mad: the Movie, by Rene Moreno, performance by Ester Hernandez, 9/1995, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Ester Hernandez - Self Help Graphics, Los Angeles, 7/1991, VHS cassette (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Portrait of the Artist: Ester Hernandez, VHS cassette (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Ester's Opening - Galeria de la Raza, June 1988, VHS cassette (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - "Let the People Speak": Part 4, Women's Pathways with Marsha Gomez and Paula Gunn Allen, n.d.,VHS cassette (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - "Let the People Speak": Southwest Indigenous Women's Regional Conference, Opening panel, n.d.,VHS cassette (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Ester Hernandez, A Defiant Eye, January, 1993, VHS cassette (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - The Art of Resistance, 1994, VHS Cassette (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Lydia Mendoza, Summer 1998, Hi 8 Video cassette (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Lucy Hernandez, photo history, 11/25/1994, 8mm Video cassette (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Dias de los Muertos, Oakland, CA, 11/1994, 8mm Video cassette (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Ester Hernadez Show at Galeria de la Raza, 6/10/1988; Entrevistas a los visitantes y a Dolores Huerta, by Jorge Herrera, audio cassette (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Latino Arts and Culture, from the series America Past and Present, National Arts and Humanities Education Program, National Museum of American Art, Smithsonian Institution, kit includes VHS cassette, study, guide, slides, and color prints (Box 53, Folder 1)
- Artist's Files, Series 6; 14 linear ft.
  In Series 6, correspondence, exhibit announcement, photographs, bill of sale, photocopied news or journal articles, and miscellaneous material can be found by an artist's last name, arranged alphabetically. Individual subseries have been created where significant material was collected by Hernandez on certain artists. In particular, Subseries 4. Lydia Mendoza, Hernandez collected costumes and other personal items of the singer known as "Songbird of the Border," and these articles are found here. Please note: Subseries 6.6 Alice Walker material is restricted. Contact Special Collections for further information.
  - General, Subseries 6.1
    - Aguayo, Sergio: "Los Chicanos" [photocopied journal article], ca. 1978 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Aguirre, Valentin: correspondence, exhibition announcement (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Alarcon, Norma: correspondence, bill of sale (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Allyn, Jerri: correspondence, exhibition announcements (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Baca, Judy: correspondence (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Bains, Amalia Mesa-: correspondence, exhibition announcements, essays, unpublished ms, photographs, miscellaneous material (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Behar, Ruth: correspondence (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Behar, Ruth. Thinking Back Through Her Mother: A Mexican Woman's Life Story, 1990 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      LSAmagazine [Literature, Science, Arts], College of Literature Science and the Arts, Fall, 1990
    - Beltran, Lola: Lola Beltran, accompanamiento: banda del Recodo de Don Cruz Lizarraga, Gas Cd-1081, compact disk, autographed by artist, 1992 (Box 97, Folder 1)
    - Benavida, Virginia: "Feminaries' magazine, 1985; bill of sale (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Bejarano, Yvonne Yabro-: correspondence, course description, journal article, miscellaneous material (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Bernardi, Claudia: correspondence, exhibition announcements (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Bill, Barbara: correspondence, photocopied news articles, photos, slides, miscellaneous material (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Broyles-Gonzalez, Yolanda: correspondence, bill of sale, photographs, slides, San Francisco, 1999 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Buenrostro, Dona Maria: photographs, slides, miscellaneous photcopied correspondence, news articles, etc. (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Campusano, Jesus (Chuy): benefit announcements, death notices, correspondence (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Cantaneda, Antonia: correspondence (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Carillo, Charlie, New Mexico artist: photographs (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - Castillo, Ana. My Father Was A Toltec, West End Press, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 18)
      autographed and inscribed
    - Castillo, Ana: correspondence, photographs, appearance announcements (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - Caton Garcia, Felicia Rose. Pos Orale!, Chican Chap Book #20, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Cervantes, Yreina: correspondence [Sybil Venegas co-correspondee] (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Cisneros, Sandra: correspondence, photograph, bills of sale, lecture announcements (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Cisneros, Sandra: photographs (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Colorado, Hortencia y Elvira: Coatlicue Theatre Co., NY production of "A Traditional Kind of Women: Too Much, Not Nuff." Announcement inscribed. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Coronado, Raul: "Selena's Good Buy: Texas Mexicans, History, y Selena Meet Transnational Capitalism" [Stanford University graduate paper?] (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Corpi, Lucha: correspondence, ca. 1985 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Corpi, Lucha: photographs, Posada de Colores, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Croy, Norma Jean: photographs, prison release party, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Drummond, Judy: correspondence, miscellaneous material (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Echeveste, Maria: photographs, 1998 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Ehrenberg, Felipe. Flagrante Delicato, exhibition booklet, Casa Lamm, Mexico, 1994 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence: slides, photographs, 1978; 1980 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Fernandez, Roberta: "Thirteen Hands Make A Rainbow": unpublished short stories (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Fernandez, Roberta. Intaglio.: A Novel In Six Stories, Arte Publico Press, Houston, TX, 1990 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Flor Ada, Alma. The Christmas Tree/El Arbol de Navidad, Hyperion Books for Children, NY, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Galvez, Daniel: Photocopied news articles on street murals, slide of same, miscellaneous materials (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Garcia, Rupert: slide presentation announcement (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Garza, Carmen Loma: exhibition announcements; Scholastic Books Phonics, Chapter Book 12. (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - Garza, Carmen Lomas: photographs, exhibitiob opening[?], 1987; house warming, 1999 (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Goldman, Shifra M.: correspondence, photocopied news articles, miscellaneous material (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Gomez, Marsha: Death notices and dedications, photocopied essays, public art proposal, miscellaneous material (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Gomez, Marsha: photographs, Austin, TX, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Gomez, Selma: miscellaneous text (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Gomez-Pena, Guillermo: performance announcements, magazine article, miscellaneous material (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Gomez-Pena, Guillermo: photographs, "Mexterminator" performance with Isis Rodriguez, 1998 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Gomperts, Hulk: correspondence, photographs, photocopied news article [partial] (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Gosling, Maureen: correspondence, catalog, script, miscellaneous material (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Gutierrez-Stavenhagen, Elia: bills of sale, postcard, photographs, slides: Tepotzlan and Xochimilco DF, Mexico, 1993; UFWA Peregrenacion, 1994 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Harlan, Theresa: correspondence, recognition award application, miscellaneous material (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Hernandez, Lourdes: correspondence, nwespaper article (Box 56, Folder 11)